A Guide to the Legislative Petitions of the General Assembly, 1776-1865
Library of Virginia
Noteworthy are the following petitions: Freeholders of Sussex County asking to be relieved from a payment made to the College of William & Mary for tobacco lands leased from the college by permitting them to pay off their rents in tobacco or in current money (1777/11/22); Inhabitants of Orange County asking that the cultivation of tobacco may be restrained in order to raise & manufacture those articles that are necessary for the accommodation of the Army & the prosecution of the war (1777/12/05); Inspectors of Rockett's Inspection asking for an act to take the half-acre lot of land adjoining the warehouse for the purpose of building a house for the reception of tobacco (includes plat) (Henrico Co. - 1789/11/12); Thomas Leiper, tobacconist from Philadelphia, asking for the repeal of the law which prohibits citizens from other states from vending snuff in Virginia (Miscellaneous (Chronological) - 1788/08/20); Manufacturers of tobacco asking for an act to prevent fraud in the branding of tobacco (Richmond City - 1835/02/11); Rocky Ridge Commissioner's report containing a list of tobacco burnt in the Rocky Ridge Warehouses in March 1873 (Chesterfield Co. - 1787/12/04); Edmund W. Rootes asking for the introduction of Benjamin Dearborn's patent balances into the tobacco warehouses of the Commonwealth (includes lithograph) (Miscellaneous (Chronological) - 1804/12/12); and the Virginia State Agricultural Society asking for the repeal of all the laws relating to the inspection of quality in the Commonwealth (Buckingham Co. - 1856/01/12).
Towns - There are 2,822 records in the database from citizens, mayors & common councils, fraternal organizations, committees, churches, lot holders, aldermen, merchants, fire companies, inspectors of tobacco, trustees, and others. These petitions concern the establishment of towns, town charters & incorporations, additions & extensions of town limits, establishment of tobacco warehouses, appropriations, schools & academies, election precincts, streets & alleys, libraries, banks, further time to improve lots, taxes, lotteries, courthouses, the appointment of trustees, canals, manufacturing companies, corporate powers, flour inspections, market houses, jails, railroads, wharves, livestock, bridges, aqueducts, lodges, cemeteries, ferries, hotel companies, and others.
Noteworthy are the following petitions: Board of Directors of the Western Lunatic Asylum protesting against being included in the extension of the corporate limits of Staunton (Augusta Co. - 1860/02/15); Robert Briggs & others asking for the incorporation of the Medical College of Virginia (Richmond City - 1835/12/23 & 1836/12/31); Citizens of Lynchburg asking for an act incorporating the town (1804/12/08); Citizens of Petersburg asking that a guard be stationed in the town to protect against insurrection (N.D.); Citizens of Richmond protesting against the bill to incorporate Hollywood Cemetery (1848/01/11); Citizens of Blacksburg asking for the establishment of an agricultural school or college in the town (Montgomery Co. - 1858/01/06); Citizens of Hampton asking for a law incorporating the town (1849/01/06); Citizens of Lexington, sufferers from the fire of 1796, asking for an act authorizing a lottery for their benefit (Rockbridge Co. - 1790/11/10); Citizens of Wheeling asking for an act of incorporation (Ohio Co. - 1805/12/04); Common Council of Richmond asking for authority to prevent the erection of wooden buildings in Richmond except under such restrictions as they may deem expedient (1840/02/18); Inhabitants of Norfolk Borough asking for an act incorporating the Marine Society of Norfolk for the single purpose of providing a fund for the relief of the distressed widows & children of any persons who may have been members of the society (1816/12/14); Inhabitants of Richmond asking for the incorporation of the town of Richmond (original missing) (1782/05/28); Inhabitants of Richmond asking for aid in the establishment of a library & depository of the arts & sciences on Capitol Square (1817/12/20); Inhabitants of Yorktown asking for an act incorporating the town (York Co. - 1780/05/10); Richard Lorton asking for permission to use the Museum on the Public Square for an Athenaeum (Richmond City - 1833/02/14); John Lynch asking for an act establishing the lots he laid off at Lynch's Ferry into a town (Campbell Co. - 1784/11/05); Mayor, Aldermen, Common Council, & Other Freeholders of Norfolk Borough asking for relief from the distress occasioned by being driven from their homes & by the burning of the town by provincial troops (1776/11/16); Mayor, Recorder, Aldermen, & Common Council of Williamsburg asking for permission & authority to raise by lottery a sum to be applied towards repairing the Capitol & building annexed to it, and establishing a fund for the support of the academy (1783/05/27); Recorder, Aldermen, & Common Council of Williamsburg asking for an appropriation for rebuilding the former Capitol, or granting the lot on which it stood to the city of Williamsburg (1832/12/10); and the Richmond Fire Association asking for permission to erect an engine house on the southeast corner of the Public Square (1841/01/06).
War Claims/Pensions - There are 1,741 records in the database regarding war claims & pensions for service during the French & Indian War, Revolutionary War, War of 1812, & Mexican War. Included are petitions from citizens, heirs, soldiers, officers, administrators, widows, executors, agents, attorneys, merchants, guardians, and others, regarding compensation for war service, compensation for supplies, ships, etc., furnished to troops during various wars, bounty lands, pensions, military certificates, depreciation of pay, George Rogers Clarke's Illinois Regiment, State Navy, Cherokee Expedition, commutation of pay, and compensation for damage in Norfolk by American troops ordered by a resolution of the Convention during the Revolution.
Noteworthy are the following petitions: Samuel & James Barron, heirs & representatives of Commodore James Barron, asking that the Auditor of Public Accounts be directed to issue to them certificates for the commutation due their father for his services as commander of the state boat Liberty during the Revolution (Elizabeth City Co. - 1793/10/29 & 1795/11/25); George Rogers Clark, Brigadier General & Commandant throughout the western jurisdiction of the Commonwealth, asking for the settlement of his general account (Kentucky Counties - 1791/11/11); Inhabitants of Sussex County asking for relief from the loss of bridges across the Nottoway River which were destroyed by the Marquis de Lafayette in 1781 to stop the progress of the British Army (1783/06/18); Inhabitants of Princess Anne, Norfolk, Nansemond, & Isle of Wight asking that measures be taken for the relief for the loss of slaves taken by the British armies in their invasions during the Revolutionary War (Princess Anne Co. - 1791/10/28); James, alias James Lafayette, former slave of William Armistead emancipated in 1786, asking for a law allowing him a small sum for his service during the Revolutionary War (New Kent Co. - 1818/12/28); William H. Richardson asking for compensation for extraordinary services as adjutant general during the Mexican War (Richmond City - 1847/12/30); and Trustees of Portsmouth asking for compensation for the loss of the market house burnt by order of General Henry Lee in January 1776 (1789/11/16).
Wills/Administrations - There are 1,072 records in the database from citizens, administrators, securities, distributes, widows, heirs, representatives, executors, agents, guardians, trustees, devisees, attorneys, legatees, and others regarding the sale of land & lots, Revolutionary War claims & bounty lands, slaves, pensions, debts owed to estates, taxes, divisions of estates, emancipations, and administrations of the mentally ill.
Noteworthy are the following petitions: Cuthbert Bullitt, representative of his late brother Thomas, Adjutant General of the regular forces raised in the state in 1775 and Deputy Adjutant General of the Southern Department in 1776, asking for bounty land for his brother's service (Miscellaneous (Chronological) - 1784/06/12); Mary Byrd, widow & executrix of William Byrd, asking for permission to sell a tract of land in Henrico & Chesterfield counties so that proceeds may be applied to the debts of the deceased (Charles City Co. - 1787/11/23); Jubal Early & others, guardian of the heirs of Abner Early, deceased, asking for a law to authorize the sale of three small pieces of mountain land (Montgomery Co. - 1841/12/30); John Frazer, Jr., executor & son of William Frazer, deceased, who was employed by the Navy Board in 1776 with John Roane to furnish supplied to the builders of ships of war on the Mattaponi River, asking for the relief from debts accrued by testator (King William Co. - 1787/11/22 & 1788/11/04); Bernard Gratz, & others, executors of George Croghan, asking for an act for securing them, and those who purchased land from them, their titles to the land which Croghan purchased from the chiefs of the Six Nations in 1749 (Miscellaneous (Chronological) - 1793/11/04); Janette Taylor & George L. Lowden, heirs of Commodore John Paul Jones, asking that provision may be made by the Legislature for the satisfaction of the land bounty granted to their ancestor by Virginia (Richmond City - 1840/12/07); and Bushrod & Corbin Washington, executors of John A. Washington, deceased, who was executor of Augustine Washington, asking for the appointment of commissioners for dividing their proportion of one-twelfth of the property and for settling & adjusting the accounts of William Carr (Westmoreland Co. - 1787/11/22).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Counties
Series II: Cities
Series III: Kentucky Counties
Series IV: Miscellaneous (Chronological)
Series V: Miscellaenous (Alphabetical)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Church, Randolph W. (Randolph Warner), 1907-1984 Virginia legislative petitions: bibliography, calendar, and abstracts from original sources, 6 May, 1776-21 June, 1782. Richmond: Virginia State Library, 1984.
Robertson, James Rood, 1864-1932. Petitions of the early inhabitants of Kentucky to the General Assembly of Virginia, 1769 to 1792, Easley, S.C.: Southern Historical Press, c1981.
Virginia State Library. Archives Division. A calendar of legislative petitions, arranged by counties: Accomac-Bedford. Richmond, D. Bottom, Superintendent of Public Print., 1908.
Separated Material
Oversized petitions have been separated to boxes 305-370.
Contents List
- Series I: Counties, 1776-1864, Extent: 309 boxes. (Box 1-260, 305-353 (Oversized))
  - Accomack County
    - 1776-1839 (Box 1)
    - 1840-1862 (Box 2)
  - Albemarle County
    - 1776-1816 (Box 3)
    - 1817-1836 (Box 4)
    - 1837-1848 (Box 5)
    - 1849-1863 (Box 6)
  - Alexandria County
    - 1846-1858 (Box 7)
  - Alleghany County
    - 1823-1862 (Box 8)
  - Amelia County
    - 1776-1830 (Box 9)
    - 1831-1858 (Box 10)
  - Amherst County
    - 1776-1800 (Box 11)
    - 1801-1833 (Box 12)
    - 1834-1856 (Box 13)
  - Appomattox County
    - 1846-1863 (Box 14)
  - Augusta County
    - 1776-1794 (Box 15)
    - 1795-1822 (Box 16)
    - 1823-1843 (Box 17)
    - 1844-1852 (Box 18)
    - 1853-1864 (Box 19)
  - Barbour County
    - 1843-1860 (Box 20)
  - Barbour County
    - 1792-1838 (Box 21)
    - 1839-1863 (Box 22)
  - Bedford County
    - 1776-1811 (Box 23)
    - 1812-1840 (Box 24)
    - 1841-1863 (Box 25)
  - Berkeley County
    - 1776-1803 (Box 26)
    - 1804-1835 (Box 27)
    - 1836-1860 (Box 28)
  - Bland County & Boone County
    - 1862-1863, 1847-1856 (Box 29)
  - Botetourt County
    - 1776-1810 (Box 30)
    - 1811-1832 (Box 31)
    - 1833-1838 (Box 32)
    - 1838-1846 (Box 33)
    - 1847-1864 (Box 34)
  - Braxton County
    - 1837-1861 (Box 35)
  - Brooke County
    - 1797-1838 (Box 36)
    - 1839-1849 (Box 37)
    - 1850-1861 (Box 38)
  - Brunswick County
    - 1778-1843 (Box 39)
    - 1844-1860 (Box 40)
  - Buchanan County & Buckingham County
    - 1860, 1776-1819 (Box 41)
    - 1821-1843 (Box 42)
    - 1844-1858 (Box 43)
  - Cabell County
    - 1809-1840 (Box 44)
    - 1841-1860 (Box 45)
  - Campbell County
    - 1782-1821 (Box 46)
    - 1822-1840 (Box 47)
    - 1841-1863 (Box 48)
  - Caroline County
    - 1776-1829 (Box 49)
    - 1830-1861 (Box 50)
  - Carroll County
    - 1842-1860 (Box 51)
  - Charles City County
    - 1780-1860 (Box 52)
  - Charlotte County
    - 1777-1860 (Box 53)
  - Chesterfield County
    - 1776-1804 (Box 54)
    - 1805-1830 (Box 55)
    - 1831-1859 (Box 56)
  - Clarke County & Craig County
    - 1836-1864, 1852-1858 (Box 57)
  - Culpeper County
    - 1776-1804 (Box 58)
    - 1807-1833 (Box 59)
    - 1833-1860 (Box 60)
  - Cumberland County
    - 1776-1825 (Box 61)
    - 1826-1862 (Box 62)
  - Dinwiddie County
    - 1777-1840 (Box 63)
  - Dinwiddie County, Doddridge County, & Dunmore County
    - 1841-1857, 1845-1858, 1776-1777 (Box 64)
  - Elizabeth City County
    - 1778-1850 (Box 65)
    - 1851-1860 (Box 66)
  - Essex County
    - 1777-1842 (Box 67)
    - 1843-1860 (Box 68)
  - Fairfax County
    - 1776-1819 (Box 69)
    - 1820-1844 (Box 70)
    - 1846-1860 (Box 71)
  - Fauquier County
    - 1776-1816 (Box 72)
    - 1817-1833 (Box 73)
    - 1835-1846 (Box 74)
    - 1847-1863 (Box 75)
  - Fayette County
    - 1831-1861 (Box 76)
  - Fincastle County & Floyd County
    - 1776, 1831-1862 (Box 77)
  - Fluvanna County
    - 1778-1863 (Box 78)
  - Franklin County
    - 1790-1849 (Box 79)
    - 1850-1861 (Box 80)
  - Frederick County
    - 1777-1811 (Box 81)
    - 1812-1830 (Box 82)
    - 1831-1838 (Box 83)
    - 1839-1852 (Box 84)
    - 1853-1861 (Box 85)
  - Giles County
    - 1806-1847 (Box 86)
    - 1848-1862 (Box 87)
  - Gilmer County
    - 1845-1861 (Box 88)
  - Gloucester County
    - 1776-1861 (Box 89)
  - Goochland County
    - 1778-1828 (Box 90)
    - 1829-1862 (Box 91)
  - Grayson County
    - 1793-1862 (Box 92)
  - Greenbrier County
    - 1777-1821 (Box 93)
    - 1822-1843 (Box 94)
    - 1844-1861 (Box 95)
  - Greene County
    - 1842-1859 (Box 96)
  - Halifax County
    - 1776-1806 (Box 97)
    - 1807-1835 (Box 98)
    - 1836-1861 (Box 99)
  - Hampshire County
    - 1776-1810 (Box 100)
    - 1811-1836 (Box 101)
    - 1837-1847 (Box 102)
    - 1848-1861 (Box 103)
  - Hancock County
    - 1848-1861 (Box 104)
  - Hanover County
    - 1777-1810 (Box 105)
    - 1811-1860 (Box 106)
  - Hardy County
    - 1786-1847 (Box 107)
    - 1848-1861 (Box 108)
  - Harrison County
    - 1784-1808 (Box 109)
    - 1809-1820 (Box 110)
    - 1821-1835 (Box 111)
    - 1836-1841 (Box 112)
    - 1842-1846 (Box 113)
    - 1847-1854 (Box 114)
    - 1855-1862 (Box 115)
  - Henrico County
    - 1777-1820 (Box 116)
    - 1821-1839 (Box 117)
    - 1840-1863 (Box 118)
  - Henry County
    - 1779-1847 (Box 119)
    - 1848-1862 (Box 120)
  - Highland County
    - 1848-1857 (Box 121)
  - Isle of Wight County
    - 1776-1861 (Box 122)
  - Jackson County
    - 1831-1864 (Box 123)
  - James City County
    - 1777-1860 (Box 124)
  - Jefferson County
    - 1804-1834 (Box 125)
    - 1835-1847 (Box 126)
    - 1848-1860 (Box 127)
  - Kanawha County
    - 1791-1830 (Box 128)
    - 1831-1847 (Box 129)
    - 1848-1858 (Box 130)
    - 1859-1861 (Box 131)
  - King & Queen County
    - 1776-1859 (Box 132)
  - King George County
    - 1776-1862 (Box 133)
  - King William County
    - 1777-1840 (Box 134)
    - 1841-1858 (Box 135)
  - Lancaster County
    - 1777-1859 (Box 136)
  - Lee County
    - 1793-1860 (Box 137)
  - Lewis County
    - 1817-1842 (Box 138)
    - 1843-1848 (Box 139)
    - 1849-1860 (Box 140)
  - Logan County
    - 1824-1861 (Box 141)
  - Loudoun County
    - 1776-1808 (Box 142)
    - 1809-1827 (Box 143)
    - 1828-1841 (Box 144)
    - 1842-1848 (Box 145)
    - 1849-1860 (Box 146)
    - 1862 (Box 147)
  - Louisa County
    - 1777-1825 (Box 148)
    - 1826-1860 (Box 149)
  - Lunenburg County
    - 1776-1847 (Box 150)
    - 1848-1862 (Box 151)
  - McDowell County
    - 1859-1861 (Box 152)
  - Marion County
    - 1842-1849 (Box 153)
    - 1850-1861 (Box 154)
  - Marshall County
    - 1835-1856 (Box 155)
    - 1857-1861 (Box 156)
  - Mason County
    - 1791-1850 (Box 157)
    - 1851-1860 (Box 158)
  - Mathews County
    - 1796-1861 (Box 159)
  - Mecklenburg County
    - 1776-1817 (Box 160)
    - 1818-1860 (Box 161)
  - Mercer County
    - 1838-1858 (Box 162)
  - Middlesex County
    - 1780-1858 (Box 163)
  - Monongalia County
    - 1781-1805 (Box 164)
    - 1806-1827 (Box 165)
    - 1828-1839 (Box 166)
    - 1840-1847 (Box 167)
    - 1848-1861 (Box 168)
  - Monroe County
    - 1799-1846 (Box 169)
    - 1847-1862 (Box 170)
  - Montgomery County
    - 1777-1820 (Box 171)
    - 1821-1848 (Box 172)
    - 1849-1862 (Box 173)
  - Morgan County
    - 1822-1858 (Box 174)
  - Nansemond County
    - 1778-1832 (Box 175)
    - 1833-1860 (Box 176)
  - Nelson County
    - 1808-1851 (Box 177)
    - 1852-1864 (Box 178)
  - New Kent County
    - 1780-1848 (Box 179)
  - Nicholas County
    - 1818-1859 (Box 180)
  - Norfolk County
    - 1777-1806 (Box 181)
    - 1807-1841 (Box 182)
    - 1842-1860 (Box 183)
  - Northampton County
    - 1776-1862 (Box 184)
  - Northumberland County
    - 1777-1859 (Box 185)
  - Nottoway County
    - 1789-1854 (Box 186)
  - Ohio County
    - 1785-1812 (Box 187)
    - 1813-1832 (Box 188)
    - 1833-1843 (Box 189)
    - 1844-1848 (Box 190)
    - 1849-1860 (Box 191)
  - Orange County
    - 1777-1836 (Box 192)
    - 1837-1856 (Box 193)
  - Page County
    - 1831-1860 (Box 194)
  - Patrick County
    - 1791-1845 (Box 195)
    - 1846-1862 (Box 196)
  - Pendleton County
    - 1790-1859 (Box 197)
  - Pittsylvania County
    - 1776-1815 (Box 198)
    - 1816-1846 (Box 199)
    - 1847-1864 (Box 200)
  - Pleasants County & Pocahontas County
    - 1852-1857, 1822-1860 (Box 201)
  - Powhatan County
    - 1778-1830 (Box 202)
    - 1831-1858 (Box 203)
  - Preston County
    - 1818-1845 (Box 204)
    - 1846-1861 (Box 205)
  - Prince Edward County
    - 1776-1836 (Box 206)
    - 1837-1863 (Box 207)
  - Prince George County
    - 1779-1863 (Box 208)
  - Princess Anne County
    - 1776-1859 (Box 209)
  - Prince William County
    - 1776-1816 (Box 210)
    - 1817-1858 (Box 211)
  - Pulaski County
    - 1839-1863 (Box 212)
  - Putnam County
    - 1849-1860 (Box 213)
  - Randolph County
    - 1789-1842 (Box 214)
    - 1843-1855 (Box 215)
    - 1856-1861 (Box 216)
  - Rappahannock County
    - 1833-1856 (Box 217)
  - Richmond County
    - 1776-1859 (Box 218)
  - Ritchie County
    - 1855-1860 (Box 219)
  - Roane County & Roanoke County
    - 1855-1862, 1839-1862 (Box 220)
  - Rockbridge County
    - 1779-1825 (Box 221)
    - 1826-1840 (Box 222)
    - 1841-1864 (Box 223)
  - Rockingham County
    - 1778-1825 (Box 224)
    - 1826-1842 (Box 225)
    - 1843-1863 (Box 226)
  - Russell County
    - 1792-1858 (Box 227)
  - Scott County
    - 1815-1861 (Box 228)
  - Shenandoah County
    - 1776-1815 (Box 229)
    - 1816-1837 (Box 230)
    - 1838-1855 (Box 231)
    - 1856-1862 (Box 232)
  - Smyth County
    - 1833-1861 (Box 233)
  - Southampton County
    - 1778-1863 (Box 234)
  - Spotsylvania County
    - 1776-1825 (Box 235)
    - 1826-1846 (Box 236)
    - 1847-1861 (Box 237)
  - Stafford County
    - 1776-1819 (Box 238)
    - 1820-1851 (Box 239)
  - Surry County
    - 1778-1858 (Box 240)
  - Sussex County
    - 1776-1854 (Box 241)
  - Taylor County
    - 1844-1860 (Box 242)
  - Tazewell County
    - 1800-1861 (Box 243)
  - Tucker County & Tyler County
    - 1857-1861, 1815-1844 (Box 244)
  - Tyler County
    - 1845-1858 (Box 245)
  - Upshur County
    - 1852-1861 (Box 246)
  - Warren County
    - 1837-1861 (Box 247)
  - Warwick County
    - 1784-1858 (Box 248)
  - Washington County
    - 1777-1814 (Box 249)
    - 1815-1833 (Box 250)
    - 1834-1860 (Box 251)
  - Wayne County & West Augusta District
    - 1843-1857, 1776 (Box 252)
  - Westmoreland County
    - 1776-1858 (Box 253)
  - Wetzel County, Wirt County, & Wise County
    - 1846-1859, 1848-1860, 1860 (Box 254)
  - Wood County
    - 1776-1830 (Box 255)
    - 1831-1847 (Box 256)
    - 1848-1858 (Box 257)
  - Wyoming County & Wythe County
    - 1850-1852, 1792-1839 (Box 258)
  - Wythe County
    - 1840-1863 (Box 259)
  - Yohogania County & York County
    - 1777-1786, 1777-1858 (Box 260)
- Series II: Cities, 1776-1865, Extent: 36 boxes. (Box 260-286, 354-365 (Oversized))
  - Alexandria (Town)
    - 1776-1846 (Box 261)
    - 1847-1861 (Box 262)
  - Fredericksburg(Town)
    - 1776-1863 (Box 263)
  - Lynchburg (Town)
    - 1791-1825 (Box 264)
    - 1826-1845 (Box 265)
    - 1846-1863 (Box 266)
  - Norfolk (Borough/City)
    - 1776-1802 (Box 267)
    - 1803-1830 (Box 268)
    - 1831-1847 (Box 269)
    - 1848-1861 (Box 270)
  - Petersburg (Town)
    - 1779-1811 (Box 271)
    - 1812-1835 (Box 272)
    - 1836-1863 (Box 273)
  - Portsmouth (Town)
    - 1777-1860 (Box 274)
  - Richmond (Town/City)
    - 1776-1791 (Box 275)
    - 1792-1809 (Box 276)
    - 1810-1817 (Box 277)
    - 1818-1826 (Box 278)
    - 1827-1834 (Box 279)
    - 1835-1840 (Box 280)
    - 1841-1846 Feb. (Box 281)
    - 1846 Dec.-1850 March (Box 282)
    - 1850 Dec.-1856 (Box 283)
    - 1857-1865 (Box 284)
  - Williamsburg (City)
    - 1776-1862 (Box 285)
  - Winchester (Town)
    - 1780-1861 (Box 286)
- Series III: Kentucky Counties, 1776-1864, Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 287-288, 366 (Oversized))
  - 1776-1789 Oct. (Box 287)
  - 1789 Nov.-1864 (Box 288)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous (Chronological), 1776-1865, Extent: 18 boxes. (Box 289-302, 366-369 (Oversized))
  - 1776-1780 (Box 289)
  - 1781-1784 June (Box 290)
  - 1784 Nov.-1786 (Box 291)
  - 1787-1791 Oct. (Box 292)
  - 1791 Nov.-1794 (Box 293)
  - 1795-1805 (Box 294)
  - 1806-1813 (Box 295)
  - 1814-1823 (Box 296)
  - 1824-1828 (Box 297)
  - 1829-1836 (Box 298)
  - 1837-1842 (Box 299)
  - 1843-1847 (Box 300)
  - 1848-1852 (Box 301)
  - 1848-1852 (Box 302)
  - 1853-1865 (Box 303)
- Series V: Miscellaneous (Alphabetical), 1748-1875, Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 303-304, 370 (Oversized))
  - Accomack County - Notice & Polls, 1851. (Box 303, Folder 1)
  - Albemarle County
    - Committee of Military Affairs - Resolution, 1861 Jan. 31. (Box 303, Folder 2)
    - Foster, John A. - Letters, etc., 1853. (Box 303, Folder 3)
    - Harris, W. A. - Letter, 1853 Feb. 25. (Box 303, Folder 4)
    - Jordan, John - Certificate, 1808 Mar. 3. (Box 303, Folder 5)
  - Amelia County (incl. Nottoway County) - Resolutions, Maps, etc., 1829 Nov. 29. (Box 303, Folder 6)
  - Amherst County - Simmons, William T. - Account, 1845 Sept. 4. (Box 303, Folder 7)
  - Auditing Board - Claim of Maj. Read of the 97th Regt. of Virginia Militia, 1863 Jan. 15. (Box 303, Folder 8)
  - Augusta County
    - Gist, Thomas - Resolution, 1784 June 4. (Box 303, Folder 9)
    - Harmon, John A. & Skinner, James H. - Letters, 1855. (Box 303, Folder 10)
    - Justices of the Peace - Endorsement, [N.D.]. (Box 303, Folder 11)
    - Kinney, William - Letter, 1845 Sept. 14. (Box 303, Folder 12)
    - Signatures
      - [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 13)
      - [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 13)
      - [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 14)
      - [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 15)
      - [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 16)
    - Stuart, Alexander - Resolution, Affidavit, & Letter, 1793. (Box 303, Folder 17)
  - Barber, Joseph A. (Endorsement only), [N.D.] (Box 303, Folder 18)
  - Barbour County (Includes Preston & Randolph Co.) - Poll, 1847 (Box 303, Folder 19)
  - Bedford County (Includes Campbell & Pittsylvania Co.) - Polls, 1848 (Box 303, Folder 20)
  - Berkeley County (Includes Alexandria & Fairfax Co.) - Fairfax, Ferdinando & West, John, etc. - Deed, 1801 Dec. 30 (Box 303, Folder 21)